Guide to the Watkins Loomis Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Watkins Loomis Records,
1883-1987
Watkins Loomis, Inc.
ca. 131,500 items (278 boxes, 42 v., 27 card file drawers)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079449
Biographical Note
Literary agency. Ann Watkins (Angeline Whiton Watkins Davis Burlingame) 1885-1967) became a literary agent in 1910 and retired in 1957. Her son, Armitage Watkins (b. 1906), continues to operate the agency. In 1980 the agency changed its name from A. Watkins to Watkins Loomis.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, contracts, and other legal documents, account books, royalty statements and other financial records, photographs, printed materials, and card files of the Watkins Loomis, Inc. literary agency. The papers deal with editorial, financial, and legal aspects of publishing, magazine, theatrical and film rights, and all other personal and professional activities of their American and English clients. Among these clients have been Michael Arlen, Frances Hodgson Burnett, Theodore Dreiser, Ernest Hemingway, Sinclair Lewis, Carson McCullers, Ezra Pound, Ayn Rand, Dorothy Sayers, Gertrude Stein, and Dylan Thomas.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 11series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts, Contracts etc.
Series III: Uncataloged Correspondence
Series IV: Uncataloged Manuscripts, Xerox Copies and Printed Copies
Series V: Uncataloged Contracts and Miscellaneous Documents
Series VI: Financial
Series VII: Old Royalty Statements
Series VIII: Card Files
Series IX: Arranged Correspondence
Series X: Arranged Manuscripts
Series XI: Arranged Documents
Subjects
A. Watkins, Inc.; Arlen, Michael, 1895-1956.; Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849-1924.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; McCullers, Carson, 1917-1967.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Rand, Ayn.; Sayers, Dorothy L. (Dorothy Leigh), 1893-1957.; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946.; Thomas, Dylan, 1914-1953.; Watkins, Ann, 1885-1967.; Watkins, Armitage, 1906-; Burlingame, Angeline Whiton Watkins Davis, 1885-1967.; American literature--20th century.; English literature--20th century.; Literature publishing.; Authors, English.; Women authors, English.; Authors, American.; Copyright.; Women in the book industries and trade.; Publishers and publishing.; Photoprints.; Literary agents.
Access Restrictions
The files of Peter DeVries and Glendon Swartwout are CLOSED until one year after each author's death except with the written permission of the current presiding officer of Watkins Loomis, Inc.
The following boxes are located off-site: Series 1, boxes 1-207; Series 2, boxes 1-69. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1982 M-82 Purchase
Alternate Formats
John Dixon Carr letters and manuscripts are on microfilm.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Adler, Polly
  - Akins, Zoë
  - Algren, Nelson
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton
  - Baker, Carlos Heard
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash
  - Barnes, Djuna
  - Bates, Herbert Ernest
  - Baum, Vicki
  - Bell, Quentin
  - Bellah, James Warner
  - Bellamann, Henry
  - Bosquet, Alain
  - Bottome, Phyllis
  - Boyle, Kay
  - Bromfield, Louis
  - Burnett, Frances Eliza Hodgson
  - Calder-Marshall, Arthur
  - Carmer, Carl Lamson
  - Capa, Robert
  - Capote, Truman
  - Cohen, Leonard
  - Creekmore, Hubert
  - Crosby, Caresse
  - Dahl, Roald
  - De Vries, Peter
  - Dowling, Eddie
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Du Bois, William Pène
  - Dunham, Katherine
  - Duranty, Walter
  - Fromme, Lynette
  - Gillette, William Hooke
  - Goudge, Elizabeth de Beauchamp
  - Hersholt, Jean
  - Horton, Edward Everett
  - Howard, Sidney Coe
  - Huston, Walter
  - Keppel, Charles
  - Lee, Laurie
  - Lehmann, John Frederick
  - Levin, Meyer
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - McCullers, Carson
  - MacGowan, Kenneth
  - Mallory, Marshall H.
  - Manship, Paul
  - Mistral, Gabriela
  - Morgan, Seth
  - Nevins, Allan
  - Oates, Joyce Carol
  - Perkins, Maxwell Evarts
  - Priestley, John Boynton
  - Pudney, John
  - Rand, Ayn
  - Reavey, George
  - Riding, Laura
  - Rodman, Selden
  - Salk, Jonas
  - Salvemini, Gaetano
  - Saroyan, William
  - Schorer, Mark
  - Scott, Frank Hall
  - Sheridan, Clare Consuelo Frewen
  - Simpson, Eileen
  - Sitwell, Dame Edith
  - Sitwell, Sir Osbert
  - Spencer, Theodore
  - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
  - Stein, Gertrude
  - Stout, Rex Todhunter
  - Travers, Pamela L.
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Van Vechten, Carl
  - Von Braun, Wernher
  - Vorse, Mary Heaton
  - Wagenknecht, Edward
  - Warren, Robert Penn
  - Webb, Jon Edgar
  - Wilde, Percival
  - Woolf, Leonard
  - Wylie, Philip
  - Yeats-Brown, Francis Charles C.
  - Zanuck, Darryl F.
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts, Contracts etc.
  - Adler, Polly
  - Arlen, Michael
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton
  - Baum, Vicki
  - Boyle, Kay
  - Burnett, Frances Eliza Hodgson
  - Cohen, Leonard
  - De Vries Peter
  - Du Bois, William Pène
  - Hemingway, Ernest
  - Laski, Marghanita
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - Pound, Ezra Loomis
  - Priestly, John Boynton
  - Rand, Ayn
  - Rinehart, Mary Roberts
  - Sayers, Dorothy Leigh
  - Sheridan, Clare Consuelo Frewen
  - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
  - Stern, Gladys Bronwyn
  - Strong, Leonard Alfred George
  - Thomas, Dylan
  - Thomas, Dorothy
  - Todd, Ruthven
  - White, Terence Hanbury
- Series III: Uncataloged Correspondence
  - Ab - Ad (misc.) (Box 1)
  - Abbe, Kathryn & Lucinda (Box 1)
  - Abbott-Smith, N. (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Jack (Box 1)
  - Acoca, Miguel (Box 1)
  - Adam, Andrew (Box 1)
  - Adams, F. Ellison (Box 1)
  - Adams, Gerald D. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Jean Ekman (Box 1)
  - Adler, Polly (Box 1)
  - Adony, Raoul (Box 1)
  - Advanier, Jerome (Jerome Vaney) (Box 1)
  - Ag - Ap (misc.) (Box 2)
  - Agar, Alida Carter (Box 2)
  - Aitchison, Mrs. G. M. (Box 2)
  - Albert, Melvin (Box 2)
  - Algren, Nelson (Box 2)
  - Alpers, Antony (Box 2)
  - Ambrose, Kay (Box 2)
  - Alsop, Reese F. (Box 2)
  - Alt, Robert (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Anna (Box 2)
  - Andrew, Prudence (Box 2)
  - Anthony, Katharine (Box 2)
  - Apple, Russell A. (Box 2)
  - Ar - As (misc) (Box 3)
  - Archer, Beth (Box 3)
  - Arking, Linda (Box 3)
  - Arlen, Michael (Box 3)
  - Armsby, Edward H. (Box 3)
  - Aronson, Theo (Box 3)
  - Asch, Sholem (Box 3)
  - Ash, Bernard (Box 3)
  - Askanasy, Ann Helen (Helen A. Mahler) (Box 3)
  - Aspler, Tony (Box 3)
  - Asquith, Herbert Henry, 1st Earl of Oxford & Asquith (Box 3)
  - Atheneum Publishers (Box 4)
  - Atherton, John (Box 4)
  - Atkins, Meg Elizabeth (Box 4)
  - The Atlantic Monthly Press (Box 4)
  - Au - Ax (misc) (Box 4)
  - Aucoin, Clifford (Box 4)
  - Aucourt, Joan (Joan Reed), "Joan Phillips" (Box 4)
  - Australia (Box 4)
  - Axelrod, Jacob (Box 4)
  - Ayala Anguiano, Armando (Box 4)
  - Bac - Bal (Misc.) (Box 5)
  - Backus, Jean L. (Box 5)
  - Badel, A. (Box 5)
  - Bahnemann, Gunther (Box 5)
  - Balchin, Nigel (Box 5)
  - Baldrige, Letitia (Box 5)
  - Baldwin, Raymond P. (Box 5)
  - Balmain, Pierre (Box 5)
  - Ban - Bat (Misc.) (Box 6)
  - Barry, Dodie (Box 6)
  - Barry, Jocelyn (Box 6)
  - Bartlett, Vernon (Box 6)
  - Bates, Herbert Ernest (Box 6)
  - Bates, Herbert Ernest (Box 7)
  - Bau - Bell (misc.) (Box 7)
  - Baum, Vicki (Box 7)
  - Baumbach, Werner (Box 7)
  - Beasley, James M. (Box 7)
  - Beaumont, Harry (Box 7)
  - Becker, Ed (Box 7)
  - Beckner, R. Bruce (Box 7)
  - Behan, Dominic (Box 7)
  - Bell, Mary Haley (Lady Mills) (Box 7)
  - Bell, Neil (Box 7)
  - Bella - Belo (misc.) (Box 8)
  - Bellah, James Warner (Box 8)
  - Bellamann, Henry & Katherine (Box 8)
  - Bellamy, Francis Rufus (Box 8)
  - Belloc, Hilaire (Box 8)
  - Belmont, Georges (Box 8)
  - Ben - Ber (misc.) (Box 9)
  - Benedict, Ralph (Box 9)
  - Phil Berg-Bert Allenberg, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Bergsma, Joan (Box 9)
  - Bevan, Aneurin (Box 9)
  - Bezzerides, A.I. (Box 9)
  - Bi - Bor (Box 9)
  - Bialoguski, Michael (Box 9)
  - Bibesco, Marthe Lucie Lahovary (Princess George) (Box 9)
  - Birch, David C. (Box 9)
  - Black, Margaret (Box 9)
  - Blades, Ann (Box 9)
  - Blair, David (Box 9)
  - Blair, Robert Alan (Box 9)
  - Blake, George (Box 9)
  - Blanton, Mary (Box 9)
  - Blish, James (Box 9)
  - Blodgett, John Gordon (Box 9)
  - Blotnick, Srully (Box 9)
  - Blumenstock, David I. (Box 9)
  - Bodley, Ronald Victor Courtenay (Box 9)
  - The Bodley Head Ltd (Box 9)
  - Bolte, Carl Eugene, Jr. (Box 9)
  - Bolte, Mary Brooks Elwell (Box 9)
  - Bonestell, Chesley (Box 9)
  - Boore, W. H. (Box 9)
  - Bos - Boyd (misc.) (Box 10)
  - Bosanquet, Mary (Box 10)
  - Bosworth, James Allan (Box 10)
  - Bottome, Phyllis (Box 10)
  - Boyd, Malcolm (Box 10)
  - Boyle, Kay (l942-1974) (Box Box 11 & 12)
  - Br... (Misc.) (Box 13)
  - Brackett, Leigh (Box 13)
  - Bradley, Gene E. (Box 13)
  - Braley, Russell N. (Box 13)
  - Bretherton, Vivian (Box 13)
  - Brickhill, Paul (Box 13)
  - Bridges, Joan (Box 13)
  - Brito, Charles A. (Box 13)
  - Brittain, Robert & Mary Zwemer (Box 13)
  - Brittain (Box 13)
  - Broad, Raymond Ferrers (Box 13)
  - Brock, Lynmar, Jr. (Box 13)
  - Brockman, W. EriC (Box 13)
  - Bromberg, Walter (Box 13)
  - Brooke, Dinah (Box 13)
  - Brooke, Edgar D. (Box 13)
  - Brooks, Anne Tedlock (Box 13)
  - Brotherton, Joe L. (Box 13)
  - Brown, James Associates, Inc. (Box 13)
  - Brown, Zenith "Leslie Ford", "David Frome" (Box 13)
  - Browne, Reg Courtney (Box 13)
  - Brownstein, Marc (Box 13)
  - Brush, Katharine (Box 13)
  - Buc - Burk (misc) (Box 14)
  - Buckingham, Nancy (Nancy Sawer), "Hilary London", Erica Quest" (Box 14)
  - Buisson, Justine Krug (Box 14)
  - Bunker, Edward H. (Box 14)
  - Burlingame, Ann Whiton Watkins Davis (Mrs. Rogers) (Box 14)
  - Burlingame, Roger (1) (Box 14)
  - Burlingame, Roger (2) (Box 15)
  - Burnett, Frances Eliza Hodgson (1905-45) (Box 15)
  - Burnett, Frances Eliza Hodgson (1960-72) (Box 16)
  - Burnett, Murray (Box 16)
  - Burns - By (misc.) (Box 16)
  - Burt, Deirdre (Box 16)
  - Butler, Peggy (Box 16)
  - Butler, Peter (Box 16)
  - Byrd, Elizabeth (Box 16)
  - Ca. (misc.) (Box 17)
  - Calder-Marshall, Arthur (Box 17)
  - Cameron, D. Y. (Dorothy M. Cook) (Box 17)
  - Campbell, Helen Jones (Box 17)
  - Capa, Robert (Box 17)
  - Cape, Jonathan, Ltd. (Box 17)
  - Carey, Grace (Box 17)
  - Carpenter, Iris (Box 17)
  - Carpenter, Margaret (Box 17)
  - Carr, John Dickson "Carter Dickson" On Microfilm (Box 17)
  - Carter, John Franklin "Ian Faircloe", "Jay Franklin" (Box 17)
  - Casey, Isabelle (Box 17)
  - Casey, Kevin (Box 17)
  - Cassell and Company Ltd. Publishers (Box 17)
  - Cavendish, Clare (Box 17)
  - Cawley, Clifford C. (Box 17)
  - Ce - Chas (Misc.) (Box 17)
  - Cecil, (Lord) David (Box 17)
  - Chandler, Raymond (Box 17)
  - Chaplin, Michael (Box 17)
  - Chapman, Charles W. (Box 17)
  - Chapman & Hall Limited (Box 17)
  - Chase, James Hadley (Rene Brabazon Raymond), "Ambrose Grant", "Raymond Marshall" (Box 17)
  - Chase, Stuart (Box 18)
  - The Children's Theatre Press (Anchorage, KY) (Box 18)
  - Childs, J. Rives (Box 18)
  - Chilton Books (Box 18)
  - (Box 18)
  - Chat - Cl (misc.) (Box 18)
  - Church, Richard (Box 18)
  - Clark, Stanley (Samuel Dubler) (Box 18)
  - Clarke, Faith (Box 18)
  - Clements, Eileen H. (Box 18)
  - Coc - Cohen (misc.) (Box 19)
  - Cochran, Howe P. (Box 19)
  - Cochrane, Shirley Graves (Box 19)
  - Codman, Charles R. (Box 19)
  - Coffin, Pat (Box 19)
  - Cohen, Edgar H. (Box 19)
  - Cohen, Leonard (1962-1965) (Box 19)
  - Cohen, Leonard (1966-1972) (Box 20)
  - Cohn - Coo (Misc.) (Box 20)
  - Cole, Margaret Isabel (Box 20)
  - Collins, L. John (Box 20)
  - Collins, W. B. (Box 20)
  - Conklin, George W. (Box 20)
  - Coogan, Tim Pat (Box 20)
  - Cooke, Hedley V. (Box 20)
  - Cookridge, E. H. "Peter Leighton" (Box 20)
  - Cooley, John K. (Box 20)
  - Cooper, Dorothy (Box 20)
  - Cooper, Frank, Associates Agency, Inc. (FCA Agency, Inc.) (Box 20)
  - Cooper, John C. (Box 20)
  - Coote, Jack (Box 20)
  - Cop - Coy (Misc.) (Box 21)
  - Copyright Office - Library of Congress (Box 21)
  - Cosmopolitan (Box 21)
  - Coster, Donald Q. (Box 21)
  - Cotta, Roger (Box 21)
  - Courtier, Sidney Hobson (Box 21)
  - Coward-McCann, Inc. Publishers (Box 21)
  - Cowell, Frank Richard (Box 21)
  - Coyle, Beatrice M. (Box 21)
  - Cr - Cu (Misc.) (Box 21)
  - Crafford, F. S. (Box 21)
  - Craig, Nancy (Box 21)
  - Cram, Mildred (Box 21)
  - Crawford, Hew T. M. (Box 21)
  - Crittenden, Jordan (Box 21)
  - Crolius, Theodore F. T. (Box 21)
  - Crook, George (Box 21)
  - Crosby, Caresse (Mary Phelps Jacob Peabody Crosby), "Rene Crevel" (Box 21)
  - Crowell-Collier Press (Box 21)
  - Crown Publishers, Inc. (Box 21)
  - Crowther, J.G. (Box 21)
  - Cu (misc.) (Box 22)
  - Cunningham, Vivian (Box 22)
  - Curry, Avon (Jean Bowden) (Box 22)
  - Curry, Tom (Box 22)
  - Curtis, Margaret E. (Box 22)
  - The Curtis Publishing Company (Box 22)
  - Curtiss, Mina (Box 22)
  - Dach, Joseph (Box 22)
  - Dahl, Roald (1944-1972) (Box 22-18)
  - Dai - Davies (misc.) (Box 29)
  - Dakers, Andrew (Box 29)
  - Dale, Alzina Stone (Box 29)
  - Dammann, Tom & Harle (Box 29)
  - Dancyger, Irene (Box 29)
  - Dane, Cleinence (Winifred Ashton) (Box 29)
  - Darden, Norman (Box 29)
  - Davidson, Frank (Box 29)
  - Davis, Arthur Kennard (Box 29)
  - Davis, Christopher (1960-1962) (Box 29)
  - Davis, Christopher (1963-1971) (Box 30)
  - Davis, E. - Day (misc.) (Box 31)
  - Davis, Ethel C. (Box 31)
  - Davis, Jack C. (Box 31)
  - Davis, Richard Harding - Copyright data (Box 31)
  - Davis, Thomas R. A. & Lydia (Box 31)
  - Davis, W. A. (Box 31)
  - Davison, Kay (Box 31)
  - De... (Misc.) (Box 31)
  - de Banke, Cecile (Box 31)
  - de Chair, Somerset (Box 31)
  - de Fuentes, Patricia (Box 31)
  - de la Condamine, Geoffrey (Box 31)
  - Delafield, Clelia (Box 31)
  - Delatiner, Barbara & Sylvia Spence (Box 31)
  - Dell Publishing Co./Delacorte Press (Box 31)
  - Delmas, Gladys (Box 31)
  - Denison, George H. (Box 31)
  - Denlinger, Sutherland (Box 31)
  - Dennis-Jones, H. & John Dowd (Box 31)
  - De Smaele, A. (Box 31)
  - Deutsch, Andre - Andre Deutsch Limited (Box 31)
  - Deverson, H.J. (Box 31)
  - Devi, Ragini (Box 31)
  - Deviak, Millorad (Box 31)
  - Devine, Frank (Box 31)
  - De Vries, Peter (1947-1972) (Box 32-35)
  - Di - Dr (Misc.) (Box 36)
  - The Dial Press, Inc. (Box 36)
  - Dibbern, George (Box 36)
  - Dick, William (Box 36)
  - Dickens, Monica (Box 36)
  - Dineen, Michael (Box 36)
  - Disney, Walt, Productions (Box 36)
  - Divine, A. David (Box 36)
  - Dobson, George F. & Millicent F. (Box 36)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, Inc. (Box 36)
  - Dole, Charles Minot (Box 36)
  - Dolliver, Barbara B. (Box 36)
  - Donaldson, Ross (Box 36)
  - Donohue, Barbara (Box 36)
  - Doubleday & Company, Inc. (Box 36)
  - Drabble, Phil (Box 36)
  - Draffin, Peter (Box 36)
  - Drama reviews (1963-1967) (Box 36)
  - Drama reviews (1967-1972) (Box 37)
  - Draper, Tom (Box 37)
  - Dresser, Chris (Box 37)
  - Du - Dy (misc.) (Box 37)
  - du Bois, William Pene (1952-67) (Box 37)
  - du Bois, William Pene (1968-72) (Box 38)
  - Duce, Margaret (Box 38)
  - Dudley, Sylvia Winsor (Box 38)
  - Dughi, Nancy (Box 38)
  - Duncan, Clyde H. (Box 38)
  - Duncan, Winifred (Box 38)
  - Dunham, Katherine (Box 38)
  - du Pont, Paul (Box 38)
  - Duranty, Walter (Box 38)
  - Dutourd, Jean (Box 38)
  - Dutton, E.P., & Co. Inc. (Box 38)
  - Dykstra, Lillian G. (Box 38)
  - Eb - Ey (misc.) (Box 39)
  - Eaton, Evelyn (Box 39)
  - Eddy, Lucy (Box 39)
  - Eddy, Roger (Box 39)
  - Edelman, Elaine (Box 40)
  - Eggerz, Petur (Box 40)
  - Einstein, Lilly Gordon (Box 40)
  - Ekman, Karl (Box 40)
  - Elliot, Gertrude (Box 40)
  - Elliott, James Gordon (Box 40)
  - Elliott, Neil (Box 40)
  - Elliott-Bateman, Michael (Box 40)
  - Endore, Guy (Box 40)
  - Ellis, Harry (Box 40)
  - Ellis, Samuel (Box 40)
  - Elwin, Malcolm (Box 40)
  - Evans, Alan "John Douglas" (Box 40)
  - Eyre & Spottiswoode (Publishers) LTD (Box 40)
  - Fa - Fe (Misc.) (Box 41)
  - Faber and Faber Ltd Publishers (Box 41)
  - Fancher, Betsy H. (Box 41)
  - Farjeon, Eleanor (Box 41)
  - Farnsworth, Clyde A. (Box 41)
  - Farrell, Barry (Box 41)
  - Fein, C. Chester (Box 41)
  - Feist, Aubrey (Box 41)
  - Fernea, Elizabeth Warnock (1963-1967) (Box 41)
  - Fernea, Elizabeth (1968-1972) (Box 42)
  - Fi - Fo (Misc.) (Box 42)
  - Fink, Merton "Matthew Finch", "Matthew Merton" (Box 42)
  - Fisher, Jeremy (Box 42)
  - Flebbe, Beulah Marie Dix (Box 42)
  - Fleming, H. Kingston (Box 42)
  - Fletcher, H.L.V. (Box 42)
  - Flood, Charles Bracelen (Box 42)
  - Ford, Phyllis (Box 42)
  - Forrest, Williams (Box 42)
  - Forster, Francis J. (Box 43)
  - Forsythe, Virginia (Box 43)
  - Foster, Michael (Box 43)
  - Fox, John P. (Box 43)
  - Fr - Fu (misc.) (Box 43)
  - Frank, Jerome (Box 43)
  - Fraser, Anthea (Box 43)
  - Frewin, Leslie, (Publishers) Limited (Box 43)
  - Freyn, Hubert (Box 43)
  - Friedman, Paul (Box 43)
  - Frost, Elizabeth Hollister (Box 43)
  - Frost, C. Vernon "Charles B. Child" (Box 43)
  - Fuller, John Frederick Charles (Box 43)
  - Funk, Peter V.K. (Box 43)
  - Funk & Wagnalls Company, Inc. (Box 43)
  - Ga - Gi (Misc.) (Box 43)
  - Geis, Irving See: Huff, Darrell (Box 43)
  - Gibbings, Robert (Box 43)
  - Gibson, Guy (Box 43)
  - Gielgud, Val (Box 43)
  - Gilot, Francoise (Box 43)
  - Glaskin, G.M. (Box 44)
  - Gle - Go (Misc.) (Box 44)
  - Gold, Rachel Rubin (Box 44)
  - Gollancz, Victor, Ltd. (Box 44)
  - Gorer, Geoffrey (Box 44)
  - Goslett, Dorothy (Box 44)
  - Goudge, Elizabeth de Beauchamp (Box 44)
  - Govaart-Halkes, Tine (Box 44)
  - Gr - Gw (Misc.) (Box 44)
  - Graham, Michael A. (Box 44)
  - Graham, Elizabeth (Box 44)
  - Graham, Phyllis (Box 44)
  - Graves, Charles (Box 44)
  - Gray, M.W. (Box 44)
  - Gray, Madeline (Box 44)
  - Green, Frederick Lawrence (Box 45)
  - Greene, Helga, Literary Agency (Box 45)
  - Greener, Leslie (Box 45)
  - Grenfell, Russell (Box 45)
  - Griffin, Stuart (Box 45)
  - Griffith, Valerie Eaton (Box 45)
  - Griffiths, Pat (Box 45)
  - Grover, Roma (Box 45)
  - Hac - Han (Misc.) (Box 45)
  - Hadfield, Alice Mary (Box 45)
  - Haestier, Richard (Box 45)
  - Haggard, Stephen (Box 45)
  - Hale, Arlene (Box 45)
  - Hale, Robert, Ltd. (Box 45)
  - Hall, Jenni (Box 45)
  - Hall, Louie E. (Box 45)
  - Hall, Melvin (Box 45)
  - Hamilton, Joyce (Box 45)
  - Hannah, Valerie (Box 45)
  - Har - Hay (misc) (Box 46)
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc./Harper's Magazine, Inc (Box 46)
  - Harris, Joanna Cochrane (Box 46)
  - Harris, Mollie (Box 46)
  - Harrison, Frank (Box 46)
  - Harrison, George Bagshawe (Box 46)
  - Hart, Hornell (Box 46)
  - Hart, Ursula Kingsmill (Box 46)
  - Hart-Davis Limited, Rupert (Box 46)
  - Harter, Walter L. (Box 46)
  - Hartigan, Francis J. (Box 46)
  - Harvey, Derek G.T. (Box 46)
  - Hatch, Alden (Box 46)
  - Hathaway, Katherine Butler (Box 46)
  - Hawkey, Arthur (Box 46)
  - Hawthorn Books, Inc. (Box 46)
  - He... (Misc.) (Box 46)
  - Heavey, Jean (Box 46)
  - Heinemann Ltd Publishers, William (Box 46)
  - Helmers, Peter (Box 46)
  - Henderson, Donald (Box 46)
  - Henley, Helen P. (Box 46)
  - Henry, Clay (Box 46)
  - Hetherington, John (Box 46)
  - Heydecker, Joe J. & Johannes Leeb (Box 46)
  - Heym, Stefan (Box 46)
  - Hi... (Misc.) (Box 47)
  - Hickler, Holly (Box 47)
  - Higham Associates, Ltd., David (Box 47)
  - Hill, Paull (Box 47)
  - Hilton, Ralph (Box 47)
  - Hinchman, Jane (Box 47)
  - Hinde, John (Box 47)
  - Hoa - Hol (Misc.) (Box 47)
  - Hobson, Warren (Box 47)
  - Hoets, Pieter J. (Box 47)
  - Hoffman, James D. (Box 47)
  - Hoffman, Michael J. (Box 47)
  - Hohman, Leslie B. (Box 47)
  - Holiday (Box 47)
  - Holt, Reinhart & Winston, Inc. (Box 47)
  - Hoo - How (misc) (Box 48)
  - Honan, Park (Box 48)
  - Hopkins, Ursula Tighe (Box 48)
  - Horley, Georgina (Box 48)
  - Houghton, Robert (Box 48)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company (Box 48)
  - Howard, Mary (Box 48)
  - Howard, Munroe (Box 48)
  - Howard, Toni (Box 48)
  - Howell, William B. (Box 48)
  - Hs - Hy (misc) (Box 49)
  - Huff, Darrell & Irving Geis (Box 49)
  - Huggett, Richard (Box 49)
  - Hughes, Cledwyn (Box 49)
  - Hughes, Helen (Box 49)
  - Hughes, Richard (Box 49)
  - Huie, William Bradford (Box 49)
  - Hull, Richard (R.H.Sampson) (Box 49)
  - Hume, Cyril (Box 49)
  - Hunt, Robert B. (Box 49)
  - Hurston, Zora Neale (Box 49)
  - Hutchinson Publishing Group Ltd (Box 49)
  - Hynam, John (Box 49)
  - I... (Misc.) (Box 49)
  - Irish, Lola (Box 49)
  - J...(misc.) (Box 50)
  - Jacobs, Lawrence I., III (Box 50)
  - Jarratt, Vernon (Box 50)
  - Jay, John M. (Box 50)
  - Jefferis, Barbara (Box 50)
  - Jennett, Sean (Box 50)
  - Jerrold, Douglas (Box 50)
  - Jex, Hope Satterthwaite (Box 50)
  - Johnson, Hewlett (Box 50)
  - Johnston, Thomas (Box 50)
  - Jolly, Erin (Sally Jolly Kelley) (Box 50)
  - Jones, Dorothy B. (Box 50)
  - Jones, Glyn (Morgan Glyn Dwr Jones) (Box 50)
  - Jones, Margaret (Box 51)
  - Jones, Pamela Guy "Pamela Brookes" (Box 51)
  - Jones, Stacy V. (Box 51)
  - Jones, Thomas (Box 51)
  - Joseph, Jules K. (Box 51)
  - Joseph, Michael, Ltd. (Box 51)
  - Jullian, Marcel (Box 51)
  - Ka... (misc.) (Box 51)
  - Kanelli, Sheelagh (Sheelagh Kanellakopoulou) (Box 51)
  - Kaplan, Joseph (Box 51)
  - Karaka, Dosoo F. (Box 51)
  - Karr, Earl R. (Box 51)
  - Karsavina, Tamara (Box 51)
  - Kata, Elizabeth (Box 51)
  - Kaye, Ivan (Box 51)
  - Ke - Ki (misc.) (Box 52)
  - Keinzley, Frances (Box 52)
  - Kellems, Vivien (Box 52)
  - Kennedy, Eva A.M. (Box 52)
  - Kennedy, Ludovic (Box 52)
  - Kennedy-Manchester case (Box 52)
  - Kenney, George C. (Box 52)
  - Kent, John (Box 52)
  - Kent, Lee (Lee Prickett) (Box 52)
  - Kessler, Alfred R. (Box 52)
  - Keyt, Diana (Box 52)
  - Kiefer, G.L. (Box 52)
  - Kimble, George H.T. (Box 52)
  - King, Clive (Box 52)
  - Kingston, Jeremy (Box 52)
  - Kinney, Harrison (Box 52)
  - Kirkbride, Ronald (Box 52)
  - Kirschen, Leonard (Box 52)
  - Kl - Ky (misc) (Box 53)
  - Klainer, Albert S. "L.T. Peters" (Box 53)
  - Kluckhohn, Frank L. (Box 53)
  - Klyhn, Joan (Box 53)
  - Knopf. Inc., Alfred A. (Box 53)
  - Koeves, Tibor (Box 53)
  - Kordes, Wilhelm (Box 53)
  - Kotker, Zane (Box 53)
  - Krasicki, (Count) Stanislas (Box 53)
  - Kugelmass, J. Alvin (Box 53)
  - Kuhn, Ferdinand (Box 53)
  - Kuhn, Gordon Leslie (Box 53)
  - Kurilecz, Margaret (Box 53)
  - Lab - Laj (Misc.) (Box 53)
  - Ladds, Charles (Box 53)
  - Ladies' Home Journal (Box 53)
  - Laidlaw, William R. (Box 53)
  - Laine, Barney (Box 53)
  - Laing, Alexander (Box 53)
  - Laiser, Letitia Preston (Box 53)
  - Lake, Carlton (l956-1964) & Francoise Gilot (Box 53)
  - Lake, Carlton (l964-1968) & Francoise Gilot (Box 54)
  - Lake, Carlton (l969-1972) & Francoise Gilot (Box 55)
  - Lake, James (Box 55)
  - Lam - Laz (misc) (Box 55)
  - Lambert, Darwin (Box 55)
  - Lane, Jane (Box 55)
  - Langdon-Davies, John (Box 55)
  - Langsdale, Richard M. (Box 55)
  - Lanier, Alice "Anne Harwood" (Box 55)
  - Laski, Marghanita (Box 55)
  - Latham, Aaron (Box 55)
  - Launay, Andre (Box 56)
  - Lauterbach, Richard E. "David March" (Box 56)
  - Lawrence, Hilda (Box 56)
  - Lawrence, Margery (Box 56)
  - Lawrie, W.H. (Box 56)
  - Lawton, Fay (Box 56)
  - Laycock, John N. (Box 56)
  - Layton, Aviva (Box 56)
  - Le. .. (Misc.) (Box 56)
  - Leary, Robert (Box 56)
  - Lee, Laurie (Box 57)
  - Lee, Lawrence (Box 57)
  - Lee, Richard Henry (Box 57)
  - Leffland., Ella (Box 57)
  - Lehmann, John Frederick (Box 57)
  - Leon, Derrick (Box 57)
  - Leonard, Constance Brink (Box 57)
  - Leonard, James (Box 57)
  - Leonard, Shirley M. (Box 57)
  - LeVarn, Carol (Box 58)
  - Levin, Meyer (Box 58)
  - Levinson, Deidre (Box 58)
  - Lewis, Alfred (Box 58)
  - Lewis, Florence C. (Box 58)
  - Lewis, Gerald E. (Box 58)